Guide to the Katherine Scott Cameron Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Katherine Scott Cameron papers
1965-1973
1965-1969
SC1029
Cameron, Katherine Scott
2 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were the gift of Katherine Scott Cameron, 2011.
Information about Access
Access: Materials are open to research use.
Biographical/Historical note
Katherine (Kit) Cameron earned her AB in English at Stanford in 1969; as a student she was active in campus theatricals, served on the Ram’s Head board in 1966/67, and participated in the overseas program at Harlaxton Manor in England, June-December 1967.
Scope and Contents note
Collection includes a scrapbook containing university forms, clippings, programs, brochures, photographs, and other memorabilia from Cameron’s student days at Stanford, 1965-1969; and outgoing letters to family, 1965-1967, discussing her social life, fashions, dorms, athletic events, excursions off-campus, and her time in the overseas program in Britain. Some of the letters were typed in the form of a newsletter she called the “Stanford Scandal Sheet.” Items of note in the scrapbook include Operation Match questionnaire (computerized dating service), memo re pre-football game activities on campus involving a cable car and photographs of the cable car, a white armband from a Vietnam War protest, 1967, and the undergraduate women’s bill of rights (re living off-campus), 1967.
Access Terms
Stanford University -- General subdivision--Students.;; Stanford University. Overseas Study Program.; Women college students--California.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1966 Jan.-Jun (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1966 Sept.-Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1967 Jan.-Feb (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1967 March-June (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1967 July-Dec (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters as "Stanford Slander Sheet" or "Stanford Scandal Sheet", 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Loose items from scrapbook [invitation, programs] p. 2-3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Loose items from scrapbook [Branner Manor booklet] p. 4-5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Loose items from scrapbook [Operation Match questionnaire] p. 6-7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Loose items from scrapbook [dance booklet] p. 12-13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Loose items from scrapbook [memo re pre-football game activities involving a cable car] p. 36-37 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Loose items from scrapbook p. 46-47 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Loose items from scrapbook [ink sketch of Cameron by W. R. Davidson] p. 56-57 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Loose items from scrapbook [ticket to Pitzer's inauguration and 2 unlabelled photographs] p. 58-59 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Loose items from scrapbook [Ram's Head program "Lock Up Your Daughters"] p. 64-65 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Loose photographs from scrapbook: campus theatrical scenes, student life, Cable Car on campus, and others, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Loose notes and cards from scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Loose programs from scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Loose clippings from scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Loose miscellaneous items from scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Slides from Harlaxton Manor, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Slides from Rag Week, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Oversize loose item from scrapbook [menu from L'Omelette restaurant] p. 34-35 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Addtional Materials, Accession ARCH.2014-094
  - Graduation (commencement) - photographs, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford in Japan - photographs, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rose Bowl - photographs, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Alumni Greece Trips - photographs, 1972, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Stanford in Britain slides, 1967; Accession ARCH.2015-008
  - Slides - Stanford in Britain IV (including field trips to Rome, Germany), 1967